<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-07-18T09:32:06-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">joe’s writing archive</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">in the mundane</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/archives/2021/03/13/in-the-mundane.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="in the mundane" /><published>2021-03-13T15:47:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-03-13T15:47:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/archives/2021/03/13/in-the-mundane</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/archives/2021/03/13/in-the-mundane.html">&lt;p&gt;Anything exciting to write about?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How ’bout the fact that I’m here to write this – another chance to capture ideas – my days are numbered. Your’s are too. There’s nothing more cliché than &lt;em&gt;that’s life&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So. Need to carry on and make the best of my time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m tickled you’re here reading this. I may not know you nor get feedback but that’s okay. I still have a chance to touch you in some way with what I share – what could be better than that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been spending time gathering ideas in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://joe.jenett.org&quot;&gt;garden (of sorts)&lt;/a&gt; – check it out and yeah, thanks for stopping by.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="archives" /><summary type="html">Anything exciting to write about?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hey Siri-you-need-more-coffee!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/archives/2020/11/19/siri.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hey Siri-you-need-more-coffee!" /><published>2020-11-19T16:37:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-11-19T16:37:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/archives/2020/11/19/siri</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/archives/2020/11/19/siri.html">&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, Kim and I were having that first cup of coffee enjoying some typical bantering that 4:30am brings. We’re a little strange like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t remember exactly what we were talking about but I said, “Hey Siri, tell Kim to go back to China.” It’s an inside joke I won’t bore you with. We understand it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, Siri asked me to confirm and I did without really listening to what she said. My bad. She sent a message to a guy named Ken I know whose last name sounds a little like “back to.” It read, “Vagina.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest is history. Thanks Siri!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="archives" /><summary type="html">A few days ago, Kim and I were having that first cup of coffee enjoying some typical bantering that 4:30am brings. We’re a little strange like that.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">poor winner, poor loser</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/archives/2020/11/09/poor-winner-poor-loser.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="poor winner, poor loser" /><published>2020-11-09T15:48:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-11-09T15:48:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/archives/2020/11/09/poor-winner-poor-loser</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/archives/2020/11/09/poor-winner-poor-loser.html">&lt;p&gt;Every American who voted in the recent election is a patriot. Whether by mail or in person and regardless of their choices, Americans participated in the process in numbers larger than I can remember. With so many people participating, the winner is the winner in my book. The “American People” have spoken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his first term, our so-called President has demonstrated poor leadership skills… in horrifying detail. He insists he’s the winner based on that narrative he concocted months before the election. He knew he was going to lose! The story goes something like this – everyone who votes against him is an evil Democrat out to get him. They all came up with mail-in voting scheme as a way to “steal the election.” Okay. Fine. Whatever. But there’s no evidence of fraud and you don’t get to suppress their votes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Move aside Bozo, there’s a real leader in the wings. Concede, wish him well and cooperate with an orderly transition. That way, you won’t go down in history as the biggest Dick to ever inhabit the White House. For once in your life, do the right thing. Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="archives" /><summary type="html">Every American who voted in the recent election is a patriot. Whether by mail or in person and regardless of their choices, Americans participated in the process in numbers larger than I can remember. With so many people participating, the winner is the winner in my book. The “American People” have spoken.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">automation and the intricacies of the mind</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/archives/2020/06/27/automation-and-the-intricacies-of-the-mind.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="automation and the intricacies of the mind" /><published>2020-06-27T10:12:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-06-27T10:12:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/archives/2020/06/27/automation-and-the-intricacies-of-the-mind</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/archives/2020/06/27/automation-and-the-intricacies-of-the-mind.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s a routine task. My feed reader doesn’t show the Pinboard user’s name as a link. In fact, it’s not even text. If I want to see that user’s pinboard page I’ve got to type it out. With the help of a simple Keyboard Maestro shortcut, I can type the user’s name to open their pinboard page. Bang!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s not the magic. The act of reading the (sometimes odd) name and remembering it long enough to type it is the real challenge. Every time I pull it off, I experience a mild sense of amazement of how the mind works. Every trick is another automation.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="archives" /><summary type="html">It’s a routine task. My feed reader doesn’t show the Pinboard user’s name as a link. In fact, it’s not even text. If I want to see that user’s pinboard page I’ve got to type it out. With the help of a simple Keyboard Maestro shortcut, I can type the user’s name to open their pinboard page. Bang!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">what to say</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/archives/2020/03/31/what-to-say.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="what to say" /><published>2020-03-31T11:45:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-03-31T11:45:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/archives/2020/03/31/what-to-say</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/archives/2020/03/31/what-to-say.html">&lt;p&gt;I’m 69 years old. I’ve outlived both of my parents, David Bowie, and Prince for starters. That’s not to say I’m free of health challenges possibly jeopardizing my own longevity, it’s just to say I am here and I am grateful especially in light of the seemingly impending doom surrounding the world at the moment. We’re not doomed but the wakeup call is duly noted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;safe-at-the-moment&quot;&gt;safe at the moment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m grateful to be in this safe place with Kim, both physically untouched by the horrific pandemic at least for now. Watching news and witnessing the death of thousands in real time is the current reality. I’m sad for those losing loved ones to this wildfire. And I’m sad for those on the front line fighting a seemingly impossible fight in light of the sorry state of affairs when it comes to our nation’s utter lack of preparedness for such a crisis. Our leaders’ priorities are not at all in line with the needs of our nation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could say more but since it’s all been said before, I doubt you want to hear it. I know I don’t want to say it. There’s more to life than the misery we’re witnessing – there has to be!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;something-jack-said&quot;&gt;something Jack said&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://copingmechanism.com/2020/im-not-ignoring-the-pandemic/&quot;&gt;Jack Baty&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I am finding it nearly impossible to think about anything other than our immediate global crisis. Even so, it is therapeutic to distract myself by writing about other, more mundane topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of survival is the realization that focusing only on dire straits (such as the current crisis represents) can be a sure path to going insane. We need balance. Life goes on despite it all and experience tells me distraction is a key to survival. It works for me anyway. It always has. Whether it’s writing about or only &lt;em&gt;thinking about&lt;/em&gt; something other than the immediate global crisis, it’s important to find balance – therapeutic indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the point if we can’t use our limited time here on earth doing what we find meaningful and accomplishing those things we’ve set out to do before our time is up! We’re all vulnerable and that’s the perfect reason to do what we do while we still can in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay safe and stay sane.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="archives" /><summary type="html">I’m 69 years old. I’ve outlived both of my parents, David Bowie, and Prince for starters. That’s not to say I’m free of health challenges possibly jeopardizing my own longevity, it’s just to say I am here and I am grateful especially in light of the seemingly impending doom surrounding the world at the moment. We’re not doomed but the wakeup call is duly noted.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">chances</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/archives/2020/02/29/chances.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="chances" /><published>2020-02-29T12:05:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-29T12:05:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/archives/2020/02/29/chances</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/archives/2020/02/29/chances.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/chance.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-thrill-of-the-game&quot;&gt;the thrill of the game&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine the chance to live out your wildest dreams. Fulfillment’s a long shot but you could buy a chance. Just imagining a win is exciting. The pleasure center triggers the imagination as the thrill of the game sets in. The odds of hitting the big one are remote but imagining the power to &lt;em&gt;change everything&lt;/em&gt; makes the game fun, unless of course, one can’t afford the price of admission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-the-street&quot;&gt;on the street&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Henry hit the streets at the end of a long journey and came to appreciate being homeless leaving his old life behind with no regrets. Life is less complicated now. A buck will buy a burger if one passes on the thought of buying a life-changing chance at the window down the street. Such a change is the last thing on Henry’s mind. He’d been there before and remembers what happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A burger would hit the spot ’bout now.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="archives" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">eye see you</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/archives/2019/09/16/eye-see-you.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="eye see you" /><published>2019-09-16T07:21:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-09-16T07:21:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/archives/2019/09/16/eye-see-you</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/archives/2019/09/16/eye-see-you.html">&lt;p&gt;When I was in the ICU following treatment for a brain hemorrhage, a doctor or nurse would stop by my bed every 10-20 minutes. They’d tell me to pull their finger and ask me things like “what year is it?”or “what’s your middle name?” They always seemed so pleased I knew all the answers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-system-in-my-head&quot;&gt;the system in my head&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I told Mike, one of the nurses, that my system was functioning fine and still running from my hospital bed. Imagining things could have been worse but still breathing, I’m creating things on a computer within and all is well. He was the one nurse who seemed to understand what I was trying to say. My stay in the ICU went on for 12 days and finally I came home. I remembered my name and there were no nasty physical symptoms – nothing to prevent me from surviving this thing intact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was nine years go and fortunately, what was done following the hemorrhage was effective. At last &lt;em&gt;inspection&lt;/em&gt;, I was given a lifetime guarantee by the physician. We both chuckled at that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;modern-medicine&quot;&gt;modern medicine&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The timing of all this was lucky – that guy who came in late at night and took care of my problem without even cutting me open had been practicing about 15 (maybe 20) years, having been one of the earlier practitioners of that type of interventional radiology. He told me stories about Neil Young and Sharon Stone having survived similar procedures and going on to live normal lives. I felt rather normal for someone who also survived it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-the-bottom-line&quot;&gt;and the bottom line&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did somebody say normal? There is no normal. What’s normal exists within each of our souls and experience. And if there’s a point to be made about normal and surviving terrible things, it’s that life goes on. Thankfully, life goes on.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="archives" /><summary type="html">When I was in the ICU following treatment for a brain hemorrhage, a doctor or nurse would stop by my bed every 10-20 minutes. They’d tell me to pull their finger and ask me things like “what year is it?”or “what’s your middle name?” They always seemed so pleased I knew all the answers</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">our reputations precede us</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/archives/2019/09/06/our-reputations-precede-us.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="our reputations precede us" /><published>2019-09-06T11:31:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-09-06T11:31:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/archives/2019/09/06/our-reputations-precede-us</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/archives/2019/09/06/our-reputations-precede-us.html">&lt;p&gt;He’s an embarrassing disaster when it comes to the &lt;em&gt;world stage&lt;/em&gt; and virtually every word he utters in public is manipulative, fabricated bullshit designed to agitate his &lt;em&gt;base&lt;/em&gt;. You and I (and probably the majority of Americans) don’t even exist in his world and he makes a mere &lt;em&gt;political animal&lt;/em&gt; seem like a teddy bear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I ain’t naming names ’cause frankly, I don’t have to.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="archives" /><summary type="html">He’s an embarrassing disaster when it comes to the world stage and virtually every word he utters in public is manipulative, fabricated bullshit designed to agitate his base. You and I (and probably the majority of Americans) don’t even exist in his world and he makes a mere political animal seem like a teddy bear.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">the groove</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/archives/2019/06/14/the-groove.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="the groove" /><published>2019-06-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-06-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/archives/2019/06/14/the-groove</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/archives/2019/06/14/the-groove.html">&lt;p&gt;When you’re in it, you know. Thoughts flow. Words flow. When you’re in the groove, anything can happen. But sometimes, it’s a struggle to find the groove. The groove lacks on-demand functionality, at least for some of us.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="archives" /><summary type="html">When you’re in it, you know. Thoughts flow. Words flow. When you’re in the groove, anything can happen. But sometimes, it’s a struggle to find the groove. The groove lacks on-demand functionality, at least for some of us.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">the nice, the crappy, and the ridiculous</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/archives/2018/04/19/the_nice_the_crappy_and_the_ridiculous.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="the nice, the crappy, and the ridiculous" /><published>2018-04-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/archives/2018/04/19/the_nice_the_crappy_and_the_ridiculous</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/archives/2018/04/19/the_nice_the_crappy_and_the_ridiculous.html">&lt;p&gt;I didn’t want to steal that other famous movie title though it certainly could apply. I’ve been &lt;em&gt;thoughts gone wild&lt;/em&gt; lately and it’ll help to put some of ‘em down. Please feel free to try this at home with your own interpretations of &lt;em&gt;good, bad, and ugly&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-nice&quot;&gt;the nice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A simple double shot of espresso. Acts of kindness. People, diverse people. Health and happiness. A homemade Italian sub. Love. Honesty. These are easy choices for me, anyway. These things are good without question in my mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-crappy&quot;&gt;the crappy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spammers, scammers, bad hackers, and thieves. Tracking and targeted advertising. Surveillance and other invasions of privacy. Bullies. Liars. Thugs. Racists. In my mind, these things, even in moderation, can be downright crappy, thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-ridiculous&quot;&gt;the ridiculous&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I have this idea that we’re all a little crappy in some ways and nice in other ways. We’re humans after all and when we interact, it matters if our &lt;em&gt;crappy&lt;/em&gt; takes over in excess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if a very-public-someone in a position of leadership lies all the time and treats other people like shit too often, many other humans are gonna notice. Add a little thug-like behavior to the mix and I’m not the only one who might call it ridiculous. It’s really not okay watching our government turning to shit on a daily basis. If it all seems normal to you, please put on your thinking cap and &lt;em&gt;nice&lt;/em&gt; pants and wear ‘em to the polling place next cycle.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="archives" /><summary type="html">I didn’t want to steal that other famous movie title though it certainly could apply. I’ve been thoughts gone wild lately and it’ll help to put some of ‘em down. Please feel free to try this at home with your own interpretations of good, bad, and ugly.</summary></entry></feed>